

Moustafa Mahmoud Ahmed Mohamed

Assistant IT Manager

Email: mustafa.mahmoud99988@outlook.com

Mobile: (+971) 543239190 Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Summary:

High-energy and dedicated System Administrator with 5 years of experience assisting colleagues in analyzing and problem-solving technical issues with workable solutions. Forward-thinking and team-oriented with a proven history of thinking strategically and initiating action to meet deadlines. Recognized by management and colleagues as an individual who takes on challenges and new responsibilities, and gets things done right.

Personal Data:

Place of Birth Asyut, Egypt.Nationality Egyptian.

Education:

Bachelor Degree of Commerce – Asyut University (2013 – 2017).

Language Literacy:

· Arabic Mother Tongue.

English Very Good Speaking, understanding and writing.

Certificates:

•	Cisco Certified Network Associate	(CCNA) – Not Certified.
•	Microsoft Certified System Administrator	(MSCA) – Not Certified.
•	Azure Fundamentals Certificate	(AZ-900) – Certified.
•	Azure Administrator Associate	(AZ-104) – in Progress.

IT Systems Knowledge:

Operating Systems:

Microsoft

- Installing, Configuring, and Administering Windows 2012 / 2016 / 2019 Server.
- Installing, Configuring, and Administering Hyper-V and Enable Cluster Failover
- · Installing, Configuring, and Administering Domain Servers.
- Installing, Configuring, and Administering Win 7 / 10 / 11.

Linux & MacOS

Good experience in managing MacOS & fair experience with Linux OS

Skills:

Personal Skills

- Ability to work on a variety of complicated problems of moderate scope and complexity where analysis
 of data and/or situations requires evaluation of multiple factors.
- Fast Learner as well as strong decision-making skills.
- Excellent communication skills, both in English and Arabic.
- Initiating planning and executing property IT projects.

Hotel Systems Experience

- Opera PMS (v5.5 and 5.6).
- Micros Workstation 5A & 6 with Simphony POS System, Enterprise Management Console (EMC) and Online Reporting and Analytics.
- Door Lock Systems and Keycard (CISA, Inhova, VisionLine, Vingcard).
- Payroll and HR System (HITS Naspro, Solution and Oasys).
- · Accounting System (iScala, Hyperion, Smartview, DMS, EPSearch and Birchstreet).
- Call Accounting and Minibar systems (TigerTMS and Hotlync).
- Backup Systems (Symantic, IronMountain onsite & offsite).
 Restaurant Reservations Systems (Viya App and ServMe).
- Spa Booking System/Sales Assistant (TAC).
- Printing Servers (SafeQ).
- Electronic Registration Cards SAMSOTECH eReg Solution.
- Ticketing System (ServiceNow)

Work Experience:

Assistant IT Manager – Hyatt Regency Dubai

(April 2023 - Current)

- Daily check of the server hardware status and take the appropriate action to remediate the hardware issues.
- Daily check the server's backup status and remediate any issues during the backup process.
- Ensure that there is an adequate inventory of all items & equipment to maintain the operation of the hotel in the event of equipment failures or faults.
- Assisting other departments in maximizing the effectiveness of the hotel's systems.
- Daily check the VMs replication status and remediates any issues.
- Ensure that all PC's are properly maintained and that only licensed software is used.
- Handle the IT Department tasks and meetings during the absence of IT Manager.
- Installed new Host servers, SAN storage, replace the old servers, configure the cluster failover and made a live migration for the VMs from the old servers to the new servers.
- Upgraded the servers from windows server 2012 to 2019 due to EOS of windows 2012.
- Implement SAMSOTECH eReg solution to reduce paper usage as part of the paperless initiative.
- · Implement guest business center computers.

Assistant IT Manager - Park Regency Sharm El Sheikh

(Nov 2020 - April 2023)

- Daily check on the backup system to ensure all IT system's data are completed with no errors.
- Check the share drives capacity and the data stored in it and report its status to the IT Manager.
- Check any request or issue reported by the users and resolve it, or contact the system vendor and coordinate with the support to fix the reported issue.
- Deliver exceptional service to the hotel guest.

- Proven excellence in handling companies request (The New York Times, Amazon and American Chamber of commerce) regarding equipment's setup and installation during the COP27.
- Assist in the inventory management and ongoing maintenance of hotel operating equipment.
- Advice IT manager about any system upgrade or new technology that improve the work environment and employee's productivity while extracting work out of the system.
- Maintaining contacts with other departments regarding the storing of critical and important data.
- Participate in meetings and online conferences during the absence of IT Manager.
- Help the employees in understanding the hotel systems and give training on IT policies and security awareness.

Information Systems Coordinator at Hyatt Regency Sharm El Sheikh (May 2019 – Nov 2020)

- Support hotel staff & guest with technical issues and setup conference meeting for hotel management.
- Installing and configuration computers and other devices (printers, photocopiers, laptops, micros workstations, kitchen printers and other devices related to the hotel operation.)
- Performing site vulnerabilities remediation according to Hyatt cyber security team guidelines and recommendations.
- Resolve tickets and incidents assigned by the global IT operation team.
- Check the user security groups, email accounts, shared email groups and system access to ensure the right privilege for every user according to their job title.
- Prepare the quarterly user rights reports for systems as requested.
- Check for any issues on the systems and servers including software and hardware issues and report it to the IT Manager.

Night Auditor at Gardenia Plaza Hotel & Resort Sharm El Sheikh (June 2017 – Dec 2017)

- Review all the income revenue and trace it and check if there some documents are missing or if there something wrong with the documents.
- Worked as front office cashier to settle the guest extra charges.

References:

Abdelhalim Ezzat – Director of Finance Park Regency Sharm El Sheikh. Ahmed Talaat – IT Manager Park Regency Sharm El Sheikh. Jocelyn Ong – Director of Finance Hyatt Regency Dubai. Amr Khalil – IT Manager Hyatt Regency Dubai.